Fujii! Don't be sad you lost to the dummies in the Special Course.
小藤井！ 输给了东大专科的笨蛋 也别太难过
I know how humiliation feels.
我很了解丢脸的感受
I pissed my pants in front of everyone!
我在大家面前尿裤子！
Compared to him, it's nothing!
比起他 你那不算什么！
Smoke one and feel better.
抽一支吧 会感觉好点
I'm not the same as you.
我和你们不一样
-What? -Meanie!
-什么啊？ -真刻薄！
Hey! Why are you looking away?
喂！你们为什么看向其它地方？
It's embarrassing having a lesson and walking at the same time.
一面上课一面走路很丢人
Plus, Mr. Smarty-pants is watching.
而且 聪明先生正看着呢
Ah, the kid you beat, Ryo Fujii.
哦 你们打败的那个孩子 藤井辽啊
Just ignore a guy like him!
无视这种人吧！
He'll never get into UTokyo anyway.
反正他永远都不会考上东大
Next! What's 145 times three?
下一题！145乘3是多少？
Damn it!
开什么玩笑！
But you do need to get a minimum of five people in, right?
但你至少得找到五个人加入 对吧？
Yeah.
没错
So you need at least one more student.
所以至少还需要多一位学生
Yeah, that's right.
是的 就是这样
You said you have someone, but when are they coming?
老师 你说你有人选了 那人什么时候才来？
That super genius student.
那个超级优秀的学生
No need to rush. They'll come.
没必要着急 会来的
You have to hurry and begin intensive study!
不行 你得赶紧了 得开始密集训练了！
That's it, tell him!
对啊 你多跟他说！
We really need you, Ms. Kishimoto!
岸本小姐 我们真的很需要你！
Ms. Kishimoto, this is for you.
岸本小姐 请慢用
This looks delicious!
哇 这看起来很美味！
Our restaurant survived thanks to you.
多亏你 这家店才活了下来
Thank you so much.
真的非常感谢
That's an exaggeration. This guy begged me to help.
你言重了 我会这么做 是因为这人求我帮忙
I don't remember begging.
我不记得我求过你
Don't be embarrassed.
不用害羞嘛
But I'm really happy. You came to our rural town.
但我真的很开心 还让你特地来我们这小地方
It's nothing, this is a nice place. Cape Taibusa is wonderful.
不 这是个好地方 大房岬真的很棒
You are so knowledgeable. Have you come here before?
你懂得真多 你之前来过吗？
Yes, once, for work.
是啊 因为工作来过
Is that so?
原来是这样啊
Thank you for the meal.
谢谢款待
-Please come again. -Thank you very much.
-欢迎再来 -谢谢
-Thank you! -I'll eat the leftovers.
-谢谢！ -我去把剩下的吃完
All clear.
好了
Sorry, I just meant to say hello, and they insisted I eat.
抱歉 我本来只想打个招呼 他们坚持要留我吃饭
It's alright. Much better than me eating with that asshole.
没事 比我和那混蛋一起吃饭好多了
Watch your language.
别这么说
He's really sorry for what happened.
那人对之前的事真的很愧疚
Don't hold a grudge.
别再怨恨他了
That's a waste of a life.
那是在浪费人生
Yes, ma'am.
是
So, how are things progressing?
所以呢？事情进行得怎么样了？
Most are in agreement,
大多都赞成了
but that one person still hasn't changed.
那人还是没变
Ah.
这样啊
Divisors of 24! Amano!
24的约数！天野！
24? 1, 2, 3, 4, 6, 8, 12, 24.
24？1、2、3 4、6、8、12、24！
Correct! Now divisors of 36, Seto!
答对了！ 下一个 36的约数 濑户！
36? Um, 1, 2, 3… what else?
36？呃…1、2、3…还有什么？
4, um…
4 还有…
6, 9, 12, 18, 36.
6、9、12、18、36
Too slow! The grade schoolers will laugh at you.
太慢了！连小学生都会笑你！
What is this punishment game? Why do we have to run?
这惩罚游戏是怎么回事？ 为什么要跑步？
Mr. Yanagi says math is Sparta.
柳老师说过 数学就是斯巴达
Ten more laps for complainers!
埋怨的人跑多十圈！
I'll do it, I'll do anything.
我做 我什么都做
What is that?
那是什么？
At my sacred school, Spartan training in these modern times?
在我神圣的学校 现在这年代还用斯巴达训练法？
Gives me the creeps. Do something!
真是让我鸡皮疙瘩 快做些什么！
I just told them to stop.
我刚请他们停止了
But Mr. Sakuragi said, "Don't meddle with the Special Course!"
“别干涉专科的事！” 樱木老师这么说
How's Fujii? I'm sure he's working as hard as ever.
藤井的状况呢？ 他跟之前一样在努力念书 对吧？
Well… Ever since he lost the contest,
这个嘛…自从输了比赛
I guess you'd call it a slump.
他好像就进入了低迷期
There's no way I can lose to those idiots.
我不可能会输给那些白痴
That was a once-in-a-decade type of accident.
那是十年一遇的意外
Fujii, don't work too hard, okay?
藤井 别努力过头了 好吗？
Don't tell me what to do, Third-Rate!
别告诉我该怎么做 三流大学！
-That's bad. -Yes.
-真是糟糕 -是
Chairman.
理事长
-Another contest? -Yes, Fujii wants to.
-另一场比赛？ -是 藤井要求的
At this rate, I'm worried about his mental health.
这样下去 我有点担心他的心理状况
Settling the score with a fair test
用公平的测试来解决纠纷
is the role of the instructor.
是教师的责任
Use the Common Test for University Admissions.
用大学入学共通考试吧
-Then nobody can complain. -Huh?
-这样就没人有意见了吧 -什么？
-Very good. -Sir! The level is too high!
-很好 -老师 那水平太高了！
It will be a good experience.
这对他们会是很好的经验
English, Math, and Literature. The test is two weeks.
语文、数学、英语三科 考试订在两周后
The Special Course student with the highest score will be counted.
专科生中 每科选取最高分
Those scores will go against Fujii's.
来和藤井一较高下
Fine. In that case, don't make the losing class disband.
明白了 这样的话 请不要解散输掉的班级
-That's… -No, the loser immediately disbands.
-这… -不 输家马上解散
-Sir! -But, Chairman.
-老师！ -不过 理事长
If you lose, you can't make a new course with a slightly different name.
要是你输了 你不能再办一个名字差不多的新课程
Swear you will never again do such petty things.
你要发誓 不再做这种下作的事
-If you can, I'll do it. -Sure
-如果你发誓 我们就这么做 -当然
No. There's too much difference in ability.
不行 他们的能力有太大差距
-Give us a handicap. -Handicap?
-给我们让几步 -让步？
How about if they get over half of Fujii's score,
如果说 得分超过藤井一半的话
the Special Course wins?
专科就算赢呢？
Not necessary.
没必要
Hang on now.
拜托等一下
We won't have the advantage with the types of questions.
专科在这种题目上没有优势
It's the Common Test!
那可是共通考试！
Fujii will definitely score over 700.
藤井肯定能得到700分以上
We could get 200 if we're lucky.
要是幸运 我们能拿到200分吧
Our kids couldn't possibly win.
这些孩子们根本不可能赢
We can't ask them to protect the Special Course.
我们不能要求他们保住专科
Have you ever thought about how they feel?
你有没有想过他们的感受？
They want to go to UTokyo, they trust us, they're fighting.
他们想上东大 他们相信我们 他们在奋斗
Are you going to abandon them?
你要这样抛弃他们吗？
Blah-blah-blah! Enough from you.
叽叽喳喳 吵死了
Hey!
那个！
You can fight somewhere else.
要吵请到其它地方吵
Hold the competition in two weeks.
总之 两周后进行比赛
No handicap.
不让步
It's agreed.
就这样说好了
I told you, there's a super genius student.
我跟你说过了 有位超级优秀的学生
Our secret weapon.
我们的秘密武器
Could it be Kosugi?
难道是小杉？
What? We're doing it again?
什么？又来？
-Are you serious? -Why did you accept that contest?
-你开玩笑的吧？ -你为什么要同意这样的比赛？
You'll have to take the Common Test on the road to UTokyo eventually.
大学入学共通考试 是考上东大必经的路
It's good to start early.
早点开始比较好
That may be true, but the contest is in two weeks.
你可能说得对 但考试就在两周后
-That's one week shorter than last time. -Yeah.
-比上次还短了一周 -对啊
If we lose, the course is gone. No way. No, no!
要是我们输了 专科就要完蛋 绝对不能 没法做到！
We have zero chance. What can we do?
胜算是零 我们该怎么做？
-Everyone calm down. -The teacher got us all here.
-大家冷静点 -都是老师把我们搞到这种地步
-What'll he do if we disband? -What will happen?
-要是我们解散 你要怎么办？ -你要怎么办？
Yeah, yeah, enough. Fine, I won't expect anything from you.
够了 吵死了！我不期望你们赢了
This time, it's a competition of the highest scores.
这次比的是最高分数
So one person is enough.
所以一个人就够了
The Special Course captain will be…
专科的队长是…
…him.
那个人
Huh?
啊？
What?!
什么？
But Kenta's not even a Special Course student.
但健太连专科的学生都不是
I scouted him. He wants to get into UTokyo.
我把他招进来了 他想进东大
-Huh? -Sir, do you know his grades?
-什么？ -老师 你知道健太的成绩吗？
-He's the lowest ranking in our year! -I don't think he even ranks!
-他是我们这年级最后一名！ -我觉得他连排名都没有
You're not much better…
你也没好多少…
No, I'm better than Kenta.
不是 我比健太强
Sir, are you serious? It's Kenta!
老师 你认真的吗？那可是健太！
Ms. Tamura. Show me Kenta Hara's grades.
田村老师 请让我看看原健太的成绩
-Huh? Alright. -Thank you.
-什么？好吧 -麻烦你了
Here you are.
这里 请看
Why? Why Kenta of all people?
为什么？ 那么多人中为什么偏偏选健太？
I don't know what he's thinking.
我真不知道他在想什么
Hey, what is this? What do you want with Kenta?
那个 怎么回事？你找健太什么事？
-One, one, one, all ones. -Speak to me.
-一…全都是一 -快回答我
Why Kenta…
为什么健太…
Ms. Mizuno!
水野老师！
Hey Kenta, starting today, these are your new classmates.
健太 今天起这些就是你同学了
-I'll study? -Yeah.
-我要学习？ -没错
Watch this.
看好了
Kenta.
健太
What's 800 plus 200?
800加200等于多少？
Hm?
嗯？
See?
你看
-I told you. -You're pretty bad too.
-我说了吧？ -喂 你也差不多吧
Sir, this has got to be a mistake.
老师 这应该是搞错了吧
What will you do?
现在要怎么办？
Nothing. The Special Course captain is Kenta.
没怎么办 专科的队长就是健太
I'm not teaching anyone who doesn't want to learn.
我不教不想学的人
-Let's go, Kenta. -Yeah.
-走吧 健太 -嗯
Hey, what is going on?
喂 这是怎么回事？
-Oh, it's you. -The Special Course captain is Kenta?
-哦 是你啊 -专科的队长是健太？
Him, in UTokyo? Give me a break.
他去东大？给我消停点吧
When will you get bored of making a fool of me?
你几时才要停止把我当傻子耍？
-You're mighty testy today. -Don't change the subject!
-你今天很暴躁啊 -不要转移话题！
Explain yourself! What is this?
给我解释 这是什么情况？
This worm could never aim for UTokyo.
这只虫子是不可能想上东大的
-Oh yeah? -You can tell by looking at him.
-是吗？ -你看他样子就知道了
He's missing a few screws up here.
他这里少了几根筋
He's always crawling on the ground, going after bugs.
他总是在地上爬 追着虫子
It's like, which one is the worm?
真是 谁才是虫子啊？
-Fujii. -You all.
-藤井 -你们全部！
None of you think he can get into UTokyo, so don't pretend!
你们没一个 觉得他能上东大 别装了！
I told you before.
我跟你说过了
Before you criticize others, fix your own personality.
在批评别人之前 先修正你的性格吧
UTokyo's impossible for you now.
现在对你来说 东大是不可能的了
-Bye. Let's go, Kenta. -Hang on.
-再见 健太 走吧 -等一下
-What's this crap? -No!
-这是什么垃圾？ -不要！
Is it really so important?
这真的这么重要？
Put it away. This is a school, not your yard.
那就给我收好 这是学校 不是你家后院
-Understand? -Stop!
-明白了吗？ -不要！
-Hey! -Kenta, go get it.
-喂！ -健太 去接啊
-Did you need to do that? -Fujii, smarten up.
-你有必要这么做吗？ -藤井 你长进点吧！
Ow.
好疼
No, Kenta!
不要 健太！
-No, stop, Kenta! -Let go, Kenta!
-不要 停手 健太！ -走吧 健太！
-Calm down. -Amano!
-冷静 -天野！
Ouch. He's the worst.
好疼 真是糟糕
Fujii, apologize to Kenta.
藤井 和健太道歉
Huh? He's the one who got violent.
什么？先动手的人是他耶
Why do I have to apologize to him?
我为什么要和他道歉？
He's not worth living.
这人连活着都不配
Hey that's enough from you.
喂 你真是够了
Hey, Kenta. Violence is never the answer.
喂 健太 暴力解决不了问题
Whoever starts it gets the blame.
谁先惹事 错就在谁
Idiot! He doesn't understand.
笨蛋！他没法明白
Anyway you don't have to twist Fujii's arm to beat him.
再说 就算不靠蛮力 你也能打败他
Huh?
什么？
Kenta, beat me?
健太能打败我？
What, in arm wrestling? Give me a break!
怎么？是要比手指相扑吗？ 说什么蠢话！
You'll compete in two weeks. There's no rush.
你们两周后就要比赛 不用着急
If you lose, all of you. You too.
要是你们输了 你们全员 包括你
Put your head on the ground and apologize to me.
给我叩头道歉
Wanna make a bet?
要打赌吗？
If I lose, I'll bow down to you.
要是我输了 我会向你下跪
If you lose, join the Special Course study camp.
要是你输了 加入专科训练
It'll never happen. Sure.
不可能会发生的 好啊
Go on, crawl on the ground.
去吧 在地上爬吧
Worm.
虫子
He's really the worst. Rotten to the core.
这家伙真是太烂了 烂透了
Are you okay, Kenta?
你还好吧 健太？
Mr. Sakuragi. Ms. Tamura wants to talk to you.
樱木老师 田村老师想跟你谈谈
Okay!
好！
I can see what you're doing.
我知道你要干什么
What's this about?
这是什么意思？
You can't beat Fujii, so you're getting Kenta to join
你赢不了藤井 所以你让健太加入
so he will pull his childhood friend Kosugi in.
他会把他的青梅竹马小杉也拉来
She's the only one who can beat Fujii.
她是唯一可以打败藤井的人
You're really a mean man.
你真是个狡猾的人啊
Listen. If you use Kenta for your own gain
听着 如果你为自己的好处利用健太
and he's harmed even a bit,
而伤害了他 哪怕一丁点
I will never forgive you.
我是绝对不会放过你的
No matter what happens, I'm never joining the Special Course.
无论怎么样 我都不会参加专科
Your secret weapon was Kosugi after all.
什么啊 原来你的秘密武器是小杉
You strategist, you.
你这战略家 真是！
I've never been targeting Kosugi.
我从来没把小杉当目标
Huh? Then why Kenta?
咦？那为什么选健太？
You want to know?
你想知道？
Come.
跟我来
You know, I didn't come to catch bugs.
那个 我不是来抓虫子的
What are you going to tell me?
你想跟我说什么 老师？
Just wait! Oh! There's one!
等一下 那里有一只！
Oof! Alright! Got it.
哈！太好了！抓到了
I caught it! Kenta.
我抓到了！健太
Look.
你看
Japanese Tiger Beetle. It sometimes looks backward,
日本虎甲虫 它有时会往后看
so it's sometimes called "the pathfinder."
所以也被称为“开路者”
It digs a hole and lives in it.
它住在自己挖的洞里
It's a vulnerable species in Gunma and Saga.
是群马和佐贺的易危物种
In Aomori, Tochigi, and Tokyo it's a near-threatened species.
在青森、栃木和东京则是近危物种
Whoa, amazing.
哇 好厉害
Why? After you went to the trouble of catching it…
为什么？ 你花了那么大力气去才抓到它…
You're curious about the wing motion?
你好奇它摆动翅膀的动作吗？
Yeah.
嗯
I have something you'll like. Come.
好 我有个你会喜欢的东西 跟我来
This is for you.
这个给你
And this.
还有这个
These are English, Math, and Literature questions.
这是过往的语数英考题
There's 60 to 90 minutes for each subject.
每科考试时间在60到90分钟之间
There are no essay questions. It's all multiple-choice.
没有论述题 都是选择题
Huh? With multiple-choice, I have a chance even if I just pick randomly!
什么？选择题的话 我就算随机作答还是有机会
If we could win that way, we wouldn't study.
要是这样能赢 我们就不用折磨自己了
Oh, yeah.
嗯 是吧
You're right, Seto.
你说得对 濑户
As he said, even if you don't know, it's important to answer every question.
就像他说的 就算不会 还是要确保回答每一题
A lot of students run out of time before the end.
很多人考试时间结束时 还没做完题
For that reason, it's a good idea to get used to the exam format.
因此 我们最好开始习惯考试的形式
I see.
原来
But I don't understand this at all.
但这个我完全看不懂
The scope of the questions is so broad.
考题的范围太广了
We really do have zero chance.
我们的胜算果然是零！
Well, don't despair.
那个嘛 不要绝望
To help your score rise even a little,
为了提高哪怕一点的分数
you're doing these.
你们今天开始得做这个
There it is. Drills again?
又来了 又是刷题？
But we've reached high school level.
但我们已经达到高中水平了
Do them five times before the contest with Fujii.
和藤井比赛之前 把它们做上五次
-Five times? -Again?
-五次？ -又来？
Most questions on the Common Test are about basic knowledge.
共通考试的大多数题目 都和基本知识有关
If you don't know, look at the answers and choose one.
要是不会 就看着答案随便选一个
Just keep doing that.
这样一直继续
And I'll tell you what you need to strengthen.
现在我要告诉你们需要强化的地方
That is…
那就是…
Vocabulary.
词汇能力
Vocabulary? What's that?
词汇能力？那是什么？
Seriously, you guys.
天啊 你们真是
Mizuno.
水野
Vocabulary. That's how many words you know.
词汇能力 意思就是你认识多少词汇
Or that you know how to use.
或是你运用它们的能力
Oh, you mean words.
啊 你是说生词
I'm already doing that.
我已经在做了
-Huh? -My third set.
-咦？ -这是第三本了
Wow, Seto! Then he's fine!
真厉害 濑户！那他就没问题了！
Typical failure.
典型的失败法
Huh? What's wrong with these?
什么？这有什么问题？
If you made a test, what answers would you choose for multiple-choice?
要是由你来出考题 你会为选择题设哪些答案？
Words that are similar but slightly different?
意思接近 但稍微不同的词？
-That's right. -Oh.
-答对了 -哦
Answer choices are usually words with similar meanings.
选择题的答案通常是意思接近的词汇
People are easily fooled by questions like that.
人们很容易被这样的考题迷惑
It's easy to mix up what you memorize.
记住的东西很容易被混淆
If you're just blindly memorizing like that,
要是你只是这样盲目地背书
you increase vague knowledge and feel like you've studied.
你只会增加模糊的知识 并以为自己已经学懂了
That's dangerous.
那很危险
Seriously?
真的吗？
The vocabulary you need is certain vocabulary.
你需要的是真正的词汇能力
I'm not just talking about English.
我说的不只是英语
First you need Japanese.
首先你得先懂得日语
Japanese? Isn't it too late for that?
日语？这不会太迟了吗？
Okay, can you tell me what "surmise" means?
那么 有人能告诉我 “忖度”的意思吗？
Um, that's, uh, you know.
咦？那是…你知道的
Um… um… I've almost got it.
呃…那个…我快要想到了
Many test takers have a poor vocabulary.
很多考生的词汇能力不足
They read their textbooks while only vaguely understanding.
他们读课本 却似懂非懂
But that vagueness will have your neck during the exam.
但这种似懂非懂 在考试时会致你的命
If your vocabulary is poor, it'll drag every subject down.
词汇能力不好 会拖累每一个科目
What should we do?
那我们该怎么做？
Good question.
好问题
I have a method for increasing vocabulary.
我有一个加强词汇能力的方法
Of these four, choose the answer. Multiple-choice.
这四个答案中选一个
1. Go to karaoke.
一 去唱卡拉OK
2. Watch movies.
二 看电影
3. Play games.
三 玩游戏
4. Read illustrated reference books.
四 图鉴
-Seto. -Illustrated reference books.
-濑户 -当然是图鉴
Wrong!
错！
-Huh? -It's games.
-什么？ -是玩游戏
-Games? -Yes, games! Mizuno.
-游戏？ -是的 游戏！水野
Okay everyone.
好了 大家
Let's play Magical Banana.
来玩神奇香蕉吧
Magical Banana? That one?
神奇香蕉？那个？
"You say banana, I say yellow."
“你说香蕉 我说黄”
Let's try it. The rules are simple.
来试试看吧 规则很简单
I give a word, and you think of related synonyms, opposites, and similar words.
我出一个词 你们想同义词、反义词和近义词
You reply with the word without breaking the rhythm.
在不打断节奏的情况下答出这个词
That's simple.
那很简单
Reply with a two-kanji compound word.
用两个汉字的词来回答
Two kanji? It's restricted?
两个汉字？还有规定啊？
-That seems way harder. -I'll start.
-变得难多了 -我开始啦
Magical weather.
神奇天气
You say weather, I say clear sky.
你说天气 我说晴天
You say clear sky…
你说晴天…
-I say sunny. You.. -No!
-我说晴朗 你说… -错了！
It has to be two kanji. Seto out. Three laps!
一定得是两个汉字 濑户出局 跑三圈！
-Seriously? -Next!
-不是吧？ -我们继续！
Magical weather. I say weather, you say clear sky.
神奇天气 我说天气 你说晴天
You say clear sky, I say rainy sky.
你说晴天 我说雨天
You say rainy sky, I say heavy rain.
你说雨天 我说豪雨
You say heavy rain…
你说豪雨…
-I say cloudy sky. -You say cloudy sky…
-我说阴天 -你说阴天…
-I don't know! -Yes!
-我不知道！ -耶！
-Hayase out! -Huh?
-早濑出局！ -什么？
Hang on, this is too hard!
等一下 这太难了
Other weather words include bad weather, stormy weather, and hot weather.
其它和天气有关的词 还有恶天、雷天、热天等等
I recommend making a list.
我建议你们列下来
This game works for anything. English, math, literature, science.
这游戏适用于任何情况 无论是语数英或理科
Following the rhythm activates your brain.
节奏能激发你的大脑
It improves memory retention.
提高你的记忆力
Refresh during a study break, or even play alone.
在学习的空档激发脑力 甚至也可以一个人玩
Do it every day and your vocabulary will definitely improve.
每天这么做 你的词汇能力肯定进步
There are tons more games that aid in studying.
还有很多帮助学习的游戏
You don't need to suffer to improve your grades.
提升成绩需要的不是埋头苦干
You need fun effort. Remember that.
而是用有趣的方式努力 记住了
Yes, sir.
是
But sir, what about Kenta?
但老师 健太怎么办？
Let him be. He doesn't need games like this.
随他吧 他不需要这种游戏
-Huh? -Doesn't need them?
-咦？ -不需要？
Huh? I think he has the worst vocabulary of all.
什么？他的词汇能力 应该是我们中最差的
He has zero vocabulary. He'd be worse than me at Magical Banana.
他的词汇能力是零 比我玩神奇香蕉还要差
Kenta, it's time to go home.
健太 该回家啦
Kenta.
健太
Kenta, aren't you hungry? Eat up.
健太 你不饿吗？吃点东西吧
We bought it for you. Don't be shy.
我们买给你的 别不好意思
Kenta, let's go to class.
健太 我们去上课吧？
Hey, Kenta!
喂 健太！
It's no use. He's been at it since yesterday.
没用的 他从昨天开始就这样了
-But still… -Let him walk until he's satisfied.
-但是… -让他走到满足为止吧
Kenta.
健太
Kenta…
健太…
TWO DAYS LATER
（两天后）
Which kanji goes in the center?
中间应该放哪个汉字？
-I know! Sky. -Correct!
-我知道了 空！ -答对了！
Yay!
好耶！
The kanji for "sky" has three meanings.
“空”的汉字有三个意思
The first is "sky" in "blue sky" and "summer sky."
第一个是在“蓝天”或是“夏天” 这些词里 它指的是“天空”
Next, is "space" used in "blank space."
接着在“空白”这个词里
It means "empty."
指的是“没有内容”
Lastly, "mishear" where it means "lie."
最后“误听”这个词里 它的意思是“谎言”
This way, you can improve your vocabulary by linking it to kanji meanings.
这样你们就能 通过联想汉字的字义加强词汇能力
Um, sir?
老师
How long are you going to leave Kenta alone?
你还要放着健太不管多久？
Don't worry about him.
别担心他
Why?
为什么？
I'm going to get him.
我下去把他带上来
No! Leave him alone!
好了 别管他！
I can't! He's a member of our team.
我没法做到！健太是我们的一员
-Hang on, Kaede! -Hey, hey!
-等一下 枫！ -喂！
I swear, those guys…
这些家伙…
Whoa, what a mess.
啊 真是乱糟糟
Oh man, what are you doing?
天啊 你在干嘛？
Kenta, you can draw in the classroom.
健太 你可以到课室里去画
-Kenta! -What are you drawing?
-健太！ -你在画什么？
No way.
不是吧？
What is all this?
这是什么？
-Give back Kenta? -Yes.
-把健太还回去？ -是的
He'd be happier in my class, don't you think?
他在我班里会更开心 你不觉得吗？
Kenta is being left out, isn't he?
健太被排挤了 对吧？
You misunderstand.
你们误会了
Kenta is in a separate room so he can concentrate.
健太在另一间课室学习 这样他才能专心…
All lies!
说谎！
You're torturing him with forced study!
你逼他学习 你在折磨他！
I'm not done talking with you!
等一下 我还没跟你说完呢！
You should see for yourself.
你应该自己看看
Come with me.
跟我来
If you're hurting Kenta,
要是你伤害健太
I'll do whatever it takes to chase you out.
我会不惜一切代价把你赶出去
Sheesh.
真是
-Are you listening? -Ah!
-你听见了吗？ -有！
Hey, Kenta.
嘿 健太
Poor thing.
可怜的孩子
I told you. You can't force him to study. It'll only make him suffer.
我说过了 不能强迫他学习 这只是在折磨他
C'mon, let's go Kenta. Okay.
来 走吧 健太 好了
Kenta.
健太
He has a habit of making that sound when he's concentrating.
健太习惯在专注时发出那种声音
Concentrating? He doesn't understand all this English and mathematics!
专注？这些英语和数学 他根本不明白！
Kenta wrote all of this.
这些全都是健太写的
Kenta did?
健太吗？
I've been his teacher for two years.
我教了他两年
He can't even do simple English.
他连简单的英语题都不能做
He could never write this!
他不可能写得出来这些！
Hey Kenta, let's play a game.
好 健太 我们来玩个游戏吧
-Oh? -Yeah, yeah.
-哦？ -嗯
-Let's start with English. -Yeah.
-从英语开始吧
Wait, these are questions from the Common Test for University Admissions.
等一下 这是大学入学共通考试的题目
-Yeah. -No, Mari. It's a game! A game.
-是的 -不 麻里 这是游戏！
-Yeah, a game, Kenta. -Yeah.
-对的 这是游戏 -嗯
-Like always, the first to finish wins. -Okay.
-和平常一样 先做完的人胜利 -好
Okay, ready? Start!
好 准备好了吗？开始！
-I'm done! -Fast!
-完成了！ -真快！
You're so fast, Kenta!
你太快了 健太！
Ms. Tamura, mark it.
田村老师 你来改吧
Ma'am, how is it? Was I right?
老师 怎么了？我有答对吗？
Tell him. How did he do?
告诉他 他答得怎么样？
A-All correct.
全…全对
Alright! Next is math.
好！接下来是数学
-Go against Amano. -Yeah.
-这次和天野比 -好
Whoa, there are lots of questions.
哇 好多题目
What's going on?
到底怎么回事？
Hey, what is this?
这是什么情况？
Let's go.
走吧
Hey, what happened? Tell me.
喂 发生了什么？告诉我
It's simple.
这很简单
I just respected Kenta's love for insects.
我只是尊重健太对昆虫的热爱
I did that too. I spent two years trying different methods.
我也这么做了 我花了两年尝试了不同的方法
I filled the classroom with insect specimens
我在教室里放满了昆虫标本
and cages filled with insects.
还有放着昆虫的笼子
But he wasn't interested.
但他不感兴趣
He couldn't even be in the room.
他甚至不能待在课室里
Of course. Everything you did was off the mark.
当然了 你做的那些全是不相干的事
Nothing but arrogant imposition.
只不过是傲慢的强求而已
He could never kill an insect.
他从来不杀昆虫
He hates specimen boxes.
他最讨厌标本箱了
He feels sorry for insects in cages.
他对笼子里的昆虫感到抱歉
He wants them to be comfortable, living freely.
他想要它们舒适地 自由地活着
Kenta had been observing wing movement.
健太一直在观察昆虫摆动翅膀的动作
So Mr. Sakuragi…
所以樱木老师…
He gave him this book.
他送了健太这本书
"A Study of Insect Flapping Wing"?
《昆虫拍打翅膀之研究》？
The leading entomology researcher at Harvard.
哈佛大学顶尖的昆虫学研究员
Professor Colin Nelson's latest thesis.
柯林·尼尔森教授最新的论文
"Everything you want to know is in here."
“你想要知道的全都在这里面”
I told him that, and he began reading it at an amazing speed.
我这么告诉他后 他便开始用惊人的速度翻阅
That wasn't enough.
这还不够
He wanted to test his own theory with Professor Nelson.
他想和尼尔森教授试验他自己的理论
So he's writing this English letter.
所以他用英语写了这封信
He's not done yet.
他还没完成
This only took a few days.
这只花了几天
All that… how?
怎么可能…怎么会？
But he's…
但他是…
I'm not surprised you didn't see it.
你没看出来很正常
Kenta has a low auditory short-term memory.
健太的听觉短期记忆很弱
He can't even do simple calculations if he hears them.
要是单靠耳朵听 他连简单的心算都不能做
He soon forgets what the teacher says.
他很快就会忘记老师说了什么
Because of that, it's easy for him to fall behind.
正因如此 学习进度才会大幅落后
But he never forgets anything he sees.
但他不会忘记看过的东西
He has a whole English dictionary in his head.
他脑袋里有一整本英文辞典
A whole dictionary?
一整本辞典？
That's not all. Look at this.
这还不是全部 看看这个
The students made this game for him.
同学们为他制作了这个游戏
Kenta was absorbed by the book,
健太被书本吸引
but he wasn't interested in tests.
但对考试不感兴趣
But the kids figured, if it was a game,
但孩子们想到 如果这是一场游戏
Kenta could enjoy it, so they came up with several.
健太就会享受了 所以他们想出了几种办法
We didn't make them do it. They all did it on their own.
我们没让他们这么做 这都是他们自发的
They are the kind of people UTokyo wants.
他们是东大要的那种人
Through trial and error and playing many games,
通过试错和玩很多的游戏
they all improved their grades.
他们全都提高了成绩
If one can't get through, they all cooperate to solve it together.
要是其中一人做不到 他们就会合作一起解决
The UTokyo Special Course has become that sort of class.
东大专科变成了这种班级
Thanks to Kenta.
多亏了健太
But even if he gets into UTokyo, will he be able to follow the lectures?
但即使是考进了东大 他能跟上那里的课程吗？
It's okay, UTokyo has a culture of transcribing lectures.
没问题的 东大有记录逐字稿的文化
A culture of transcribing?
记录逐字稿？
They take turns transcribing the professor's lecture.
学生们会轮流记录教授的教学内容
There are a lot of people with developmental disabilities at UTokyo.
东大里也有很多发展障碍者
When did you first realize his talents?
你是什么时候发现他的才能的？
Several weeks ago, on a sunny day with a cloudless sky.
几周前 一个万里无云的晴天
He suddenly said heavy rain would fall.
他忽然说会下大雨
No weather report predicted it.
天气预报里没说
"How did you know?" I asked him.
我问他：“你怎么知道的？”
How did you know it would rain?
你怎么知道会下雨的？
The ants were closing the doors.
那些蚂蚁在关门
Ants?
蚂蚁？
March 23, 2019.
2019年3月23日
Saturday, 12:42, the ants blocked their nest.
星期六12点42分 蚂蚁堵住了它们的巢
At 2:32 p.m., rain fell.
下午2点32分 下雨了
Thursday, April 2, 2020. 6:08 p.m., the ants blocked their nest.
2020年4月2日星期四 下午6点8分 蚂蚁堵住了它们的巢
8:23 p.m., rain fell.
8点23分下雨了
Ant's body hair and antennae are sensitive to flavor, sound and temperature.
蚂蚁身上的毛发和触角 对气味、声音和气温都很敏感
They can feel the air pressure change when the humidity changes.
湿度转变时 它们能感受到气压变化
They cover their nest before it gets flooded.
它们会在水淹到蚁巢之前堵住它
Date, time, weather. He remembered it all exactly.
日期、时间、天气 他都准确记得
Then he derived a rule from the data.
然后再从这些数据中推导出规律
Observation, insight, memory, all impeccable.
观察、洞见、记忆都无可挑剔
He has what it takes for UTokyo.
他有上东大的一切条件
I couldn't see it.
我竟然没发现
I've failed as a homeroom teacher.
我这班主任真是失败
I'm not saying that.
我不会这么说
Working with a kid with a developmental disability
教育一个有发展障碍的孩子
is no small feat.
不是容易的事
You did well.
你做得很好了
You tell just by looking at him.
你看看他就知道
-I did it! I did it! -Oh, Kenta!
-做到了 我做到了！ -哦 健太！
-I did it. -Show her.
-我做到了 -让她看看
Ms. Tamura, mark it.
田村老师 请帮我看看
Mari, I did it.
麻里 我做到了
Yeah.
嗯
Since joining the Special Course,
加入专科后
he's talked about you two a lot.
他一直提起你们两位
Even if you missed the mark,
即使你没注意到他的天分
he knows that you did a lot for him.
他知道你为他做了很多
Your feelings reached him.
你的心意他都收到了
You were there for him
你一直支持着他
and made school a place
把学校营造成一个
where he could feel safe.
让他感到安心的地方
That's the most important part of developing talent.
这是培养才能最重要的部分
Yes…
是…
Ms. Tamura! Ms. Tamura!
田村老师！
Mark Amano's too!
也看看天野的答案！
Yes, okay.
嗯 好
Yeah, yeah.
嗯
I think you can beat Fujii.
我想你们应该能打败藤井
It won't be so simple.
没那么简单
Look at Kenta's marks.
看看健太的分数
He only got half marks in English.
他英语只拿到一半的分数
His reading is 100 but his listening is zero.
他的阅读是100分 但听力是零分
That's not all. Look at Literature.
还不只这样 看看语文
Classics and memorization are fine,
古文和记忆的部分没问题
but reading comprehension and questions about the intention of the author
但有关作者意图的阅读理解和问题
are difficult for Kenta.
对健太来说就很难了
What can we do?
我们能怎么办？
Nothing.
没怎么办
That's just how he is.
健太就是这样的人
The rest of them have to do their best.
其他的孩子们得尽力
If they don't, I'll have to put my head to the ground for the first time.
不然 我就得献出 人生第一次的叩头道歉了
I never did it in my biker gang days.
没当暴走族以后 我就没再做过了
You eat a lot more than you look.
看不出你那么能吃呢
It was good. Thanks.
很好吃 谢谢你
Kosugi, you really won't go to university?
小杉 你真的不会上大学吗？
Yeah.
嗯
That's a waste.
真浪费
Kenta would be so happy if you joined.
要是你加入专科 健太会很开心的
What are you saying?
你想说什么？
Ah.
啊
You heard, from Mr. Sakuragi.
樱木老师说 健太他
Kenta is working really hard.
很努力地学习
But he can't do listening and literature…
但他没法做听力题和语文…
What's this?
这是什么？
You're the fourth person.
你是第四个
"Free gyoza coupon, Setoya"?
“免费饺子券 濑户家”？
You know, Fujii said these horrible things to Kenta.
那个 藤井对健太说了很糟糕的话
This contest is so Kenta can beat Fujii.
这次比赛也是为了让健太打败藤井
We want to help him win. Please!
我们想帮忙他赢 拜托你了！
-Good evening. -Welcome.
-晚上好 -欢迎
-Hayase, Hayase!
-欢迎光临 -早濑！
Oh, it's Hayase and Kosugi.
咦？是早濑和小杉
Oh, uh, this is…
哦 这是…
Uh…
那个…
Bribing Kosugi instead of studying?
有空贿赂小杉 而没时间学习？
You don't have to say it like that.
老师 不用说到这份上吧
I had to. We'll just hold him back.
没办法啊 谁叫我们在拖他后腿
Kenta's working so hard.
健太那么努力
It's embarrassing, but it's reality.
虽然很不甘心 但事实就是这样
You've finally realized your own abilities.
你们终于意识到自己的能力了
Like you said,
像你刚刚说的
it would be hard for you to win against Fujii as you are now.
现在的你们很难赢得了藤井
But losing is a good experience too.
但输也是个不错的经验
-Hey. -Sir.
-喂 -老师
The Special Course would really be eliminated!
这样下去 专科真的会解散！
You'll have to kneel.
老师你也要下跪！
We'll deal with that when it comes.
到时候到说吧
-Ramen, please. -Yes, sir.
-请给我一碗拉面 -好的
RYO FUJII VS UTOKYO SPECIAL COURSE CONTEST DAY
（藤井辽对上东大专科 比赛当天）
If we lose, will the Special Course really get disbanded?
要是我们输了 专科真的会解散吗？
Don't be scared.
别害怕
We've done what we can.
我们已经尽力了
Yeah.
嗯
More importantly, has anyone seen Kenta?
比起这件事 有人看到健太吗？
Sir!
老师！
It's Kenta!
是健太！
Any word from Kenta?
有健太的消息吗？
He's probably looking at bugs.
他大概是在看虫子吧
Actually, Mr. Sakuragi is gone too.
其实 樱木老师也不见了
He was here this morning.
他今早还在这
The test will begin soon.
考试要开始了
Chairman. Kenta isn't here yet.
理事长 健太还没来
And Mr. Sakuragi, too.
还有樱木老师也是
Time waits for no one.
时间不等人
Or do you think the real exam will wait for you?
难道真正的考试会等你们吗？
Kenta!
健太！
-I'm not going. -But…
-我不去 -但是…
The test is starting.
考试要开始了
You played games and studied hard with everyone.
你和大家玩了那么多游戏 那么努力学习
I'm not going. I'm not going to UTokyo.
我不去 我不去东大
You have 70 minutes.
考试时间为70分钟
The first subject is math.
第一科是数学
Now, begin.
那么 考试开始
Fujii told me.
藤井跟我说
Researchers at UTokyo kill insects.
东大的研究员会杀昆虫
ONE HOUR BEFORE
（一小时前）
Kenta, before the test, I'll show you something good.
健太 考试之前我给你看点好东西
Look, an insect dissection.
看 昆虫解剖
Hey, look at it.
喂 看清楚
You'll do it at UTokyo. Dissection.
你在东大也要这么做 解剖
No, no. I won't.
不要…我不会的
Don't you know?
你不知道吗？
Why are bugs so easy to stomp?
为什么虫子那么容易就被踩死？
Their lives
它们的生命
are not necessary.
没有存在的必要
They're useless. They're in the way.
它们没什么用处 只是碍人碍事而已
They're annoying. Get it?
它们很烦人 你明白了吗？
Just like you. Unwelcome!
就像你一样 是多余的！
It's like Fujii said.
就像藤井说的
I can't be like everyone.
我没法像其他人一样
I can't even do simple things.
我连简单的事都做不了
I'm in everyone's way.
我只是在阻碍大家
I'm causing trouble.
只会给大家添麻烦
I'm unwanted.
我是多余的人
An unwanted life, huh?
多余的生命 是吧？
There's no such thing!
没有这种东西！
So what, you can't do things?
你不能做一些事 那又怎么样？
That's why you have friends!
所以你才需要朋友啊！
They're all taking that test as well as they can.
他们都在拼命考试
They want you to win.
为了让你赢得这场比赛
Everyone came to ask me.
大家都来找我
To join the Special Course so they could defeat Fujii for you.
要我参加专科 为了能帮你打败藤井
Do you still think your life is unwanted?
你还觉得你是多余的人吗？
If you can't do things, are you in the way?
你不能做一些事 就代表你拖累人了吗？
Are insects that are easily killed at man's convenience
那些为了人们自己方便 而轻易杀死的昆虫
in the way just by living?
难道因为活着就拖累人了吗？
Are they harmful?
他们有害吗？
No.
不
No, no, no!
不！
Creatures that harm just by living
光是因为活着就有害的生物
don't exist on Earth.
地球上不存在这样的东西
Insects
昆虫
are part of the ecosystem.
是生态系统的一部分
For the natural world,
对大自然来说
humans cause more harm.
人类造成的伤害更大
They destroy the ecosystem.
他们破坏生态系统
They kill more than they can eat.
他们杀的比吃的多
That's not okay.
不应该是这样的
All life is equal.
所有生命都是平等的
We mustn't kill.
我们不应该杀它们
If you think so,
如果你这么认为
you have to make that world.
就由你来创造出那样的世界吧
Change society.
改变社会
Break the mold.
打破框架
Make a future that's in harmony with insects.
创造一个可以和昆虫共存的未来
How?
怎么创造？
If you become a researcher, maybe you can.
要是当上了研究员 或许你就能做到
I'll get you into UTokyo.
我会帮你考进东大
The rest is up to you.
剩下就靠你了
Kenta.
健太
You don't have to do it the same as others.
你不用和其他人一样
There's a way that will work for you.
会有适合你的方式的
I'll go!
我去！
I'll go to UTokyo.
我会去东大
I'll go to UTokyo!
我会去东大！
Alright.
好！
Causing trouble just by living?
因为活着就带来麻烦？
I'll never let you say that again!
我绝对不允许你再这么说！
Okay!
好！
Sir.
老师
I…
我…
It's your life.
这是你的人生
You decide.
你自己来决定
Kenta! Kosugi?
健太！小杉？
-I'll take the test. -Huh?
-我会参加考试 -什么？
But there's only 20 minutes left for math.
但数学只剩下20分钟
Yeah. It's okay.
嗯 没问题
Me too.
我也…
I'll join the Special Course.
我也要参加东大专科
Hang on. What is this?
等一下 这是怎么回事？
I can't? I just got motivated now.
不可以吗？我现在有了动力
I'm not saying you can't.
也不是不行
Alright, I'll take the test.
好 那我也参加考试
That's ridiculous. How can this be allowed?
真是荒谬 怎么能允许这种事？
I can't do this.
我做不了了
You.
你
Turning tail and running?
是想夹着尾巴逃跑吗？
Huh?
什么？
Yes!
好耶！
Sit.
坐下
What happened with Kenta?
健太发生什么事了？
How could he…
他怎么…
I have a question for you.
我有一个问题
Why did you accept Kenta Hara into this school?
你为什么接受原健太入学？
Do you think we accepted anyone because we were below capacity?
你以为我们是新生少 所以随便什么学生都收吗？
You didn't?
不是吗？
Are you mocking me?
你还真是瞧不起我啊
Listen. Out in the world, there are lots of different people.
听着 出社会会遇到各种人
The students will join society.
这些学生未来进入社会
They have to join hands with everyone and live together.
必须跟各种人合作共同生活
Respecting diversity and cooperating with one another.
我希望学生能学会
I wanted them to learn that.
尊重多元 互相协力
So even if a child with a learning disability wanted to join,
所以有学习障碍的孩子想要入学时
I put them in the regular class.
我将他放进普通班
I thought you only had mean thoughts,
我以为你只有刻薄的想法
but you have good ideas too.
没想到你也有些好理想
I could develop Kenta's talent
我之所以能开发健太的才能
because of your school's free attitude that didn't force him to study.
是因为你们学校自由的校风 没有强迫他学习
Resistance and aversion to studying?
厌恶和抗拒学习？
He had almost none.
他完全不会
So when he did begin studying,
所以当他一开始学习
he absorbed knowledge at an amazing rate.
他就以惊人的速度吸收知识
Students should be free to express their individuality.
学生应该能自由地展现他们的个性
People don't learn by being forced to study.
强迫学习并不会让人学到什么
But it's not okay to just let people go unchecked.
但也不能只是放任人不受约束
People have a natural urge to try to improve.
人自然会有想要进步的冲动
When they're ready, students will break out of their shells and bloom.
当他们准备好时 这些学生都会绽放
The role of the teacher is to take that sleeping curiosity
教师的角色是找出那沉睡的好奇心
and stimulate it.
并刺激它
Am I wrong?
我有说错吗？
The grading of all subjects has finished.
那么 所有科目的考卷已经批改完成
Here are the results.
现在公布结果
Mr. Oyama.
大山老师
Each subject is worth 200 points.
每一科目的满分是200分
From Fujii.
从藤井开始
Literature.
语文
169 points.
169分
-Whoa. -Really?
-哇 -不是吧？
English.
英语
170 points.
170分
Seriously?
认真的吗？
Math.
数学
162 points.
162分
Next, the UTokyo Special Course marks.
接下来 东大专科的最高分
Literature, Kosugi.
语文 小杉
175 points.
175分
Yeah! Yeah!
好耶！
You're amazing.
你真厉害
English.
英语
Kosugi.
小杉
179 points.
179分
-We won two! -Huh?
-我们两胜了 -什么？
-Yeah, we won! -Yay!
-耶！我们赢了！ -耶！
Yeah! Yeah!
太好了！
We won! We won!
我们赢了！
-Yay! -Woo!
-太好了！ -耶！
Quiet!
安静！
Lastly.
最后
Math.
数学
Kenta Hara.
原健太
Amazingly,
居然
198 points.
获得了198分
Huh?
什么？
Kenta…
健太…
Yay!
太好啦！
Kenta!
健太！
You're amazing!
你太厉害了！
Wow, Kenta!
哇 健太！
Kosugi, your scores are amazing!
小杉 你的语文和英语也很厉害！
Bullshit…
开什么玩笑…
This is bullshit!
开什么玩笑！
This is totally unacceptable.
真是无法接受
Fujii.
藤井
This is bullshit…
开什么玩笑…
I've…
我…
Do you know how hard I…
我有多努力…
Fujii.
藤井
You did well.
你做得很好
This is your highest score yet, right?
这已经是你的最高分了 对吧？
As promised,
按照规定
we will disband the Elite University Course today.
我们今天会解散一流大学课程
But this isn't your fault.
但这不是你的错
Exactly. The reason for the defeat is elsewhere.
说得对 你失败的原因在别处
Do you know? Chairman.
你知道是什么吗 理事长？
It's because you let a student battle alone.
因为你让一个学生孤军奋战
Fujii worked hard, but he didn't have any teammates. That's the reason.
藤井很努力 但他没有任何队友 这就是原因
Teammates? Is this kindergarten?
队友？这是青春漫画吗？
It's clearly proven by data.
数据已经清楚证明
People who aim for UTokyo as a group pass the exam much more often.
和群体一起挑战东大的人 更有机会通过考试
Say, a rural public school.
比如说 一间乡村的公立学校
Maybe one student per year gets accepted into UTokyo.
或许一年会有一位学生考进东大
That student carries the expectations of the whole town.
那位学生要背负着整个小镇的期望
They go to the exam as a member of the away team.
他们作为远处团体的一员去参加考试
And how about famous prep schools?
那些有名的重点学校呢？
Every year, a number of students go to take the exam.
每年都会有一群人去参加考试
"If they can do it, so can I."
“要是他们能做到 我也能做到”
In this way, they help each other improve.
以这种方式 他们帮助彼此进步
On the day of the exam, the room is full of familiar faces.
到了考试那天 考场里都是熟面孔
Who has the upper hand? You know the answer.
谁占优势？你已经知道答案了
The UTokyo Special Course aims for it as a group.
东大专科是以一个团体去挑战的
If you want to get into UTokyo, you can join us.
要是你想进东大 你可以加入我们
Who would study with these idiots?
谁会想和这些笨蛋一起学习？
We are taking this seriously here.
我们可是很认真的！
I could never.
我绝对不要
First, you need to apologize to Kenta.
首先 你得和健太道歉
Yeah! Apologize!
对啊 道歉！
I'd rather die than apologize.
我宁愿死也不会道歉
Are you really going to quit, Kosugi?
小杉 你真的要退出吗？
Yes. I'm not interested in university.
是的 我对大学没兴趣
Please take care of Kenta.
请好好照顾健太
With your grades, not going to university is a waste.
但你的成绩不上大学 真的很可惜
Why not?
为什么不上呢？
You could get into UTokyo.
是你的话 能考上东大的
It's a huge opportunity.
这是你人生中一个很大的机会
If your parents are opposed,
要是你父母反对
I could talk to them.
我可以和他们谈谈
Don't get involved!
别再干涉了！
Pardon me.
不好意思
Mari.
麻里
Mari, Mari, Mari.
麻里…
See you tomorrow.
明天见
Yeah.
嗯
Don't give me that shit!
说什么蠢话！
Say that again!
你敢再说一次！
How could a woman
一个女人怎么还想
go to university! How insolent!
上大学了！真是无耻！
Mari… Mari…
麻里…
You are not going to university!
你不会去大学的 对吧？
You're not going!
说你不会去！
A study camp from hell?
地狱集训学习营？
You have poor reading comprehension.
你们毫无阅读理解能力
I invited a special instructor.
我请来了一位特别讲师
The Spartan instructor?
斯巴达讲师吗？
This one is even scarier.
这次的更可怕
-Why are you here? -Fair's fair.
-你怎么也在？ -输了就是输了
A trick we can use for all subjects? What a deal!
一个所有科目都能用的技巧？ 真是划算！
100 words in 10 minutes?
十分钟内一百字？
-You too. -Uh, me?
-你也要 -我也要？
Ready, start!
准备 开始！
Why a banana?
很好吃 但干嘛吃香蕉？
Eat with energy efficiency in mind.
吃的时候要考虑能量摄取效率
Tomorrow at 6 a.m., in uniforms in front of the Dragon Zakura.
明天早上六点穿制服在龙樱前集合
-Yay! -You're amazing.
-太好啦！ -你真厉害
Okay, get up!
好了 起床了！
I was having a good dream!
我刚在做一场好梦耶
If you're not expected to pass,
被我判定没有希望录取的人
you'll be made to quit the course.
我会叫他退出东大专科
Subtitle translation by: Claire Tanaka
字幕翻译：赵慈宇